<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Unicoder]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Unicoder]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/unicoder/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 15:34:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/unicoder/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Top Albums of Each Decade and How They Influenced Guitar Sales | Reverb]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Top Albums of Each Decade and How They Influenced Guitar Sales | Reverb</h1><p>Microcephalic writers again get it WRONG. It was CLAPTON NOT PAGE that started the resurgence on the Les Paul for Christ sake can't you f.cking mindless minions of media hype ever get it right?! Clapton started the Les Paul craze with his historic Bluesbreakers LP (called the Beano sessions) in 1966 and was the FIRST to plug the Gibson into a Marshall and begin a sound that would forever alter the landscape of electric Plectrum guitar which Page himself admitted to in a Guitar Player magazine interview but again, you writers NEVER f.cking get right and apparently never will. Page used a Tele (as well as Beck) and didn't touch a Les Paul (at least publicly) until well AFTER Cream broke up plus Zeppelin did not release their first LP until 69 which featured Page on a 1958 Fender Telecaster NOT Les Paul. Clapton, during the Bluesbreakers & early Cream (before he used his iconic SG) made the Les Paul so desirable, that Gibson eventually re-issued it in 1968 the second year of Cream's existence. Regardless of what various internet bullsh.t might say, I talked to an old time Gibson custom shop master who told me he "remembers the talk about this British guy named Eric Clapton, creating a new demand for the old Les Paul so after many meetings, the company decided to re-issue it since the SG at the time was not doing as well as we hoped but soon would". He went on to say, "Clapton really knocked up Gibson solid body sales by later using the SG and Firebird, so he more than any other, catapulted sales of our solid bodies between 1966 & 1969. So Eric not only made the Les Paul a hit, he later made the SG a huge must have solid body."It was EC (not the deified Hendrix) that influenced more electric players than anyone since Charley Christian, Wes Montgomery and Chuck Berry. Hendrix himself was a Clapton fan, a BIG one and if any of the moronic readers know the true history as opposed to history revisionism, they'll know that Hendrix only agreed to go with Chandler to England on the condition he could meet the great Eric Clapton and the rest is history (JH also proceeded to meet Townsend and Beck but it was Clapton that he was focused on because he had been knocked out by the Bluesbreaker LP which had been available in limited quantities in the US and all the "hip" pro guitarists were on to it, I should know, I WAS THERE!)Jimi not only immensely respected EC, he called him his "white soul mate" and if anyone watched the video of Hendrix performing a TV show with Mary Ann Faithfull (its on YouTube), they'll note how when she comes over to join him for 'Hey Joe', he defies her by deciding to instead say, "we dedicate this next song to Cream, Eric Clapton, Jack Bruce & Ginger Baker" and proceeds to play Sunshine of Your Love. He did this in deference to the fact, Cream was disbanding. Did U know Hendrix was in the audience during Cream's farewell performance at the LA Forum (October 19, 1968) which can be heard on the Goodbye Cream LP live tracks? No wonder Eric's playing is so inspired, just check out the solos and ending to the live Sitting on Top of the World...I'm sure EC did that for JH. Check Jimi's Touragraphy, he was touring the LA area at that time.The two guitarists enjoyed a mutual love fest. During a Hendrix concert in late 68 a fan up front yelled out to Hendrix "are you better than Clapton" to which Hendrix replied "is your girlfriend better than mine":-)</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/d8029ff9c9d10380a3141f0875430b09dadabf9e.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://reverb.com/news/the-top-albums-of-each-decade-and-how-they-influenced-guitar-sales?_aid=tank</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1c6a101d-60c0-4bcc-85df-deefe9386ae2</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 15:34:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triskelion v.2]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Triskelion v.2</h1>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/unicoder/triskelion-v2/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">219b970d-2f40-4c11-9636-9d551e097061</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:44:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wanna be Jimmy Page?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wanna be Jimmy Page?</h1>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/unicoder/wanna-be-jimmy-page/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">aef4e4ae-61f1-4f67-83dd-6dd5bcfcc3d0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:44:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jimmy Page: "I Never Heard the Song" in "Stairway to Heaven" Lawsuit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Jimmy Page: "I Never Heard the Song" in "Stairway to Heaven" Lawsuit</h1><p>Jimmy Page says he had never heard the Spirit song he is accused of copying until he was sued for allegedly plagiarizing it. Speaking in court last week, the Led Zeppelin guitarist stood by his claim that the opening to his classic track "Stairway to Heaven" did not copy a signature guitar passage from Spirit's song "Taurus," which appeared on the American group's self-titled 1968 debut album.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/376c881826ee6567567498f1f66cc5e5cc4c9790.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.guitarplayer.com/artists/1013/jimmy-page-i-never-heard-the-song-in-stairway-to-heaven-lawsuit/56857</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">552629c6-28f2-499b-bcf8-8ff1ff43db11</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:44:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experience Hendrix with Dweezil]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Experience Hendrix with Dweezil</h1><p>Experience Hendrix at Kings Theatre on Fri. Mar 18, 8:00 PM</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/unicoder/experience-hendrix-with-dweezil/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7bbe56c6-d2f8-4eaf-a594-89ce466b38d6</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:44:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wayne Shorter and Herbie Hancock's Open Letter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wayne Shorter and Herbie Hancock's Open Letter</h1>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/unicoder/wayne-shorter-and-herbie-hancocks-open-letter/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">35411b3a-64a0-438c-8bf1-58fe3fc5f97e</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:44:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sir George Martin, rip]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Sir George Martin, rip</h1><p>The greatest argument for George Martin's musical genius may be this: He had an open mind and was willing to take what he later called "a calculated risk" in auditioning and signing The Beatles. Think about that. Martin didn't like their "old stuff," a bunch of cover tunes, or their "mediocre" originals.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/be16a44771c03f9f37c1d75aef53d0f7e6574515.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://reverb.com/news/george-martin-the-producer-who-took-a-calculated-risk-on-the-beatles</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">849e16fa-e949-41bf-970e-b67b9aa3fbdb</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:44:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>